A Guide to the Valleda Pittard Chandler letters, 1938-1944
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Valleda Pittard Chandler letters, 1938-1944
The Library of Virginia
45113
1.35 cu. ft. and 3 boxes
Valleda Pittard Chandler
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of James Gray Chandler of Orange Park, Florida.
Biographical Information
Valleda Pittard was born 13 December 1920 in Mecklenburg County, Virginia, to William J. Pittard (1882-1973) and Sallie T. Ragland Pittard (1884-1975). Valleda Pittard attended Madison College in Harrisonburg, Virginia, graduating in December 1942. She began teaching in Bedford County, Virginia. Valleda Pittard married George Graham Chandler (1915-1948) of Mecklenburg County, Virginia, in 1945, and they had one son. Valleda Pittard Chandler taught school and was a volunteer for the American Cancer Society. She died in South Boston, Virginia, 12 July 1999 and was buried in the Buffalo Baptist Church cemetery in Mecklenburg County.
Scope and Content
Letters, 1941-1944, to Valleda Pittard (Chandler) from her future husband George Graham Chandler (1915-1948) of Mecklenburg County, concerning their courtship and engagement, his army service, his return to civilian life, her schooling and teaching, and general and family news; correspondence, 1941-1942, from Robert Holden Wrenn (1923-2007) of Randolph-Macon College and Herndon, Virginia, regarding his education at Randolph-Macon, her education at Madison College, visits between the two, and general news; and correspondence from family and friends of Valleda Pittard concerning school, World War II, family news, and general news.
Contents List
- Letters, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letters, January-February 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters, March 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters, April 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters, May 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters, June-July 1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters, August 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters, September 1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Letters, October 1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters, November 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Letters, 1-15 December 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Letters, 19-31 December 1941 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Letters, 2-16 January 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Letters, 18-29 and no date January 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Letters, 2-13 February 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Letters, 14-25 and no date February 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Letters, 1-13 March 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Letters, 16-31 March 1942 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Letters, 1-15 April 1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Letters, 21-28 April 1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Letters, 1-15 May 1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Letters, 16-25 May 1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Letters, June-July 1942 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Letters, August 1942 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Letters, September-October 1942 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Letters, November 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Letters, December 1942 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Letters, no date [1942?] (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Letters, January 1943 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Letters, February 1943 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Letters, March 1943 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Letters, April 1943 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Letters, May-June 1943 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Letters, July 1943 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Letters, August 1943 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Letters, September-October 1943 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Letters, November-December 1943 and no-date, but post-September 1943 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Letters, January-February 1944 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Letters, March 1944 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Letters, April 1944 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Letters, May 1944 (Box 3, Folder 16)